<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sections on Iris Margetis</title>
    <link>/sections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sections on Iris Margetis</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="/sections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/sections/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sections/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research experience spans topics in environmental and development economics,  neighborhood dynamics, poverty, and forced migration. Across these roles, I have supported faculty and supervisors alike through data cleaning, analysis, and visualization of results for presentations and publications using Stata, R, and ArcGIS Pro, often working with large administrative datasets and spatial data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-experience&#34;&gt;Research Experience&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Assistant&lt;/strong&gt;, Dr. Anna Maria Santiago, Michigan State University, 2022–present&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Conduct data analysis and spatial modeling on poverty, neighborhood effects, and low-income homeownership using Stata, R, and ArcGIS Pro. Contributed to one published article and several co-authored manuscripts under review, while also gaining experience with large-scale national housing datasets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/sections/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sections/teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Teaching is one of the most meaningful parts of my academic life. I love helping students engage with complex ideas, develop confidence in their own thinking, and see the relevance of economics in the world around them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;teaching-experience&#34;&gt;Teaching Experience&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Teaching Assistant, EC 302: Intermediate Microeconomics, Michigan State University, Spring 2021&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Teaching Assistant / Guest Lecturer, EC 202: Introduction to Macroeconomics, Michigan State University, Fall 2021&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Teaching Assistant, EC 301: Intermediate Microeconomics, Michigan State University, 2019–2020 (2 semesters)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-interests&#34;&gt;Teaching Interests&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Courses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sections/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a PhD Candidate in Environmental, Urban, and Applied Microeconomics at Michigan State University.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My research focuses on how mandatory flood risk disclosure laws for rental properties affect rental housing markets, rent prices, and sorting patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My dissertation examines these dynamics in two U.S. states—Indiana and Texas—leveraging proprietary housing data, geospatial risk information, and natural experiments around policy implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More broadly, I am interested in the growing reliance on rental housing, climate adaptation, and the role of real estate markets in shaping household exposure to natural hazards. My work explores how people respond to new information, the extent to which they value it, and how state and federal policies can both support adaptation and potentially reinforce existing inequities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sections/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;margetis@msu.edu&#34;&gt;margetis@msu.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Phone&lt;/strong&gt;: +1-330-631-5856&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Office&lt;/strong&gt;:  Berkey 5J, 509 E Circle Dr, East Lansing, MI 48824 (Economics)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/iris-margetis-492146149/&#34;&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/iris-margetis-492146149/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/sections/personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sections/personal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was born in the United States and grew up in Greece, which sparked my love for cultures, languages, and stories early on. I&amp;rsquo;m an avid reader and traveler, and I’m happiest when exploring new places, meeting new people, and learning how others live and think. I’m also a huge movie fan and quite possibly the biggest foodie you&amp;rsquo;ll ever meet — I truly believe you can’t understand a place without understanding its food culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
